Ramin Yavari

Phone: +98 935 240 8836 ● Email: sir.raminyavari@gmail.com

Senior Full-Stack Developer with more than 11 years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and maintaining software applications. Having a deep understanding of SQL and no-SQL databases, data structures, and algorithms. Skilled in server-side programming languages such as C# and Java-EE. Solid experience in client-side development with pure JavaScript and Reactjs. Familiar with other technologies such as Docker, Hadoop, Apache Lucene, and Solr.

Experience

2012-06 - Full-Stack Developer

Present

InKnowTex Ltd. • Tehran, Iran

- Designed and developed an enterprise CMS solution.
- Supervised the product development and testing process.
- Conducted several meetings with customers to design suitable solutions.
- Trained and mentored more than 25 junior programmers.
- Investigated and applied state of the art technologies and algorithms to ensure that the company will remain as the leader of the market.
- Implemented security guidelines and checked them periodically.

Key achievement: Designed a highly configurable enterprise software solution to address knowledge and content management problems with approximately 50 organizational customers, each with more than 500 employees.

2006-02 -

Software Developer

2012-06

Freelance • Isfahan, Iran

- Developed a social network analysis software.
- Developed a graph analysis tool that could recognize isomorphic graphs.

Key achievement: Developed some commercial software products, and boosted competencies in programming, software solution design, and development.

Notable Projects

Form Builder & Poll Service

Designed and developed a form builder that provides facilities to store and search highly structured organizational contents.

2017 Enterprise Problem Resolution Application

Designed and developed an enterprise QA service to facilitate problem-solving

throughout the organization.

2016 Enterprise Wiki

Designed and developed an enterprise wiki software which provides tools for collaborative content creation and management.

2015 Enterprise Social Network

Designed and developed an enterprise social network which enhances collaborations within a content management solution.

Education

2010 - 2012 Master of Science, MBA

University of Tehran • Tehran, Iran • 4.0 GPA

2006 – 2010 Bachelor of Science, IT Engineering

Isfahan University of Technology • Isfahan, Iran • 4.0 GPA

Skills

JavaScript

Excellent

React

Excellent

Java

Advanced

SQL

••••• Excellent

HTML5 & CSS3

••••

Excellent

C#

••••• Excellent

Database Design

••••• Excellent

Security

•••••
Intermediate

Personal Qualities

Quick Learning

Effective Listening

Punctuality Responsibility

Languages

Kurdish

Native

Farsi

Native

English

•••••

Excellent